Ramin Ala

Electrical Engineer

- **J** +1 506-262-9550
- ✓ ramin.ala@gmail.com
- in Linkedin
- Website
- ₹ 780 Montgomery St., Fredericton, NB, Canada

SUMMARY

I am an electrical engineer with eight years of industrial experience between 2010 and 2019. After that, I joined the University of New Brunswick as a Ph.D. student and also worked as a teaching assistant. During my doctoral studies, I gained valuable experiences in data science. I completed two relevant courses with outstanding grades (earning A+ in both), and a part of my thesis focused on the application of data science. I am currently in the final stages of defending my Ph.D. at the University of New Brunswick and actively seeking employment opportunities.

Please feel free to visit my website, where I am gradually adding more information. You can find it here.

EDUCATION

• Ph.D. 2019 – 2023

University of New Brunswick

New Brunswick, Canada

Thesis: Efficient and Ultra Low Mass Harmonic Radar

Transponders for Insect Tracking Applications

• M.Sc. 2007 – 2010

K. N. Toosi University of Technology

Tehran, Iran

• **B.Sc.** 2002 – 2007

University of Isfahan Isfahan, Iran

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Iranian Space Research Center

2016 - 2018

*Tehran, Iran*Senior RF Designer

• Ertebatat Baregheh Pardis

Tehran, Iran

Senior RF Designer

• OTS 2010 – 2014

Tehran, Iran

RF and Microwave Engineer

SKILLS

• Skills Category (ex: Languages)

your skills. (ex: c, c++, etc)

SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY

• Some of the industrial tools:

Computer Simulation Technology (CST)
Altium Designer

PathWave Advanced Design System (ADS)Ansys HFSS

• Programming and other Tools:

R (Programming language)MATLAB

LaTaX

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- 1. R. Ala, C. D. Rouse and B. G. Colpitts, "An Extra Low-Mass Harmonic Radar Transponder for Insect Tracking Applications," in *IEEE Transactions on Radar Systems*, vol. 1, pp. 146-154, 2023, doi: 10.1109/TRS.2023.3286270.
- 2. R. Ala, B. Ahmadi, "A comparative study of high-power low-pass filters for satellite communications," *Microw Opt Technol Lett*, 2019; 61: 1968-1971. doi: 10.1002/mop.31783.

REFERENCES

| 1. Dr Chris Rouse | Professor at UNB | chris.rouse@unb.ca |
|-----------------------|------------------|-----------------------|
| 2. Dr Bruce Colpitts | Professor at UNB | colpitts@unb.ca |
| 3. Dr Berent Petersen | Professor at UNB | Brent.Petersen@unb.ca |

2014 - 2016